Guide to the William Dwight Franklin and the Continental Vocalists Collection, 1853 - 1867
William Dwight Franklin and the Continental Vocalists Collection, 1853 - 1867
- Music Books and Notebooks
  - Music Publications (Folder 6)
    - Peace on Earth from Dedicated to Purchasers of The Marchal & Smith Pianos and Organs, 8 West Eleventh Street, New York. Triumphant in a Thousand Contests! Christmas Waltzes
    - Payne's Musical Monthly: Published by Lyman Payne, Dealer in Pianos, Organs, Sheet Music, Music Books, and Small Musical Instruments of Every Description, No. 10, March, 1885, Middletown, Conn.
    - Thy Light Is Come from Thy Light Is Come: Sacred Song for Christmas Music, by Albert J. Holden. New York, 1887
    - The Vox Humana: A Journal of Music & Musical Information, June 1875, Hartford, Conn.
  - Incomplete Pieces (Folder 7)
    - Beautiful Sunset, written by W. Dexter Smith, Jr. Music by Jean Foster- cover of publication only
    - The Country Lassie and Her Mother Sung by the Alleghanians.
    - Cousin Jedidiah
    - Delehanty and Hengler's New and Original Songs and Dances - cover of publication only
    - Dreaming of Home and Mother Song and Chorus. Poetry and Music by John P. Ordway. M.D. - cover of publication only
    - Ever of Thee Melody by Foley Hall, Arranged as Voacl Quartette by Henry Tucker
    - The Lord is My Sheperd
    - My School Boy Days
    - Pretty Peggy. Irish Song and Dance Sung with Immense success by Pat Rooney, Irish Character Vocalist - cover of publication only
    - Shamus O'Brien. Answer to 'Nora O'Neal' A Beautiful Song and Chorus by Will. S. Hays.
    - Six Songs by Gustav Heyner
    - Swinging on the Gate: As Sung by Miss Alice Harrison in the Extravaganza of Hiawatha by Edward E. Rice.
    - Tell Me, Ye Winged Winds Sacred Chant Composed and Arranged as a solo or quartette by C. Everest.
    - That Husband of Mine - cover of publication only
    - The Vocalist; A Collection of Trios, Quartettes, Choruses, etc. - cover of publication only
    - Waiting
    - We Stand Beneath Our Flag Soldiers Chorus from Gounod's Faust, Words by W. Dexter Smith Jr. Arranged by Leslie.
    - Which Way is Your Musket A-P'intin' To-Day?
    - Who'll Save the Left, A Battle Scene, Words by R. Tompkins, Music by Geo. F. Root.
    - The Wings of a Dove As Sung with Great Applaude by Mrs. Wood
  - Published Sheet Music by W.D. Franklin or Continental Vocalists (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - A Hundred Years to Come
    - Birth of Washington
    - Come Unto Me
    - Cottage by the Glen
    - Dream Faces
    - I'm Never Alone
    - Let Us Love Each Other Fondly
    - Little Blind Boy or You and I
    - Love Launched a Fairy Boat
    - My School Boy Days
    - Old Man's Soliloquy
    - Our Heroes
    - Saved by Clinging to the Cross
    - Sweet Dreams
    - Sweet Sprig with the Breath of the Mountain
    - The Sword of Bunker Hill
    - There is Light Beyond the River
    - Those Trusting Eyes
    - The Voyage of Life
    - Widow McGee
  - W.D. Franklin Quadrill Book (Folder 2)
    - Glyde Water
    - Untitled work, W.D. Franklin, Middletown, September 1874
    - Yankee Doodle, Spangler, W.D. Franklin
    - Capricio
    - The Previous for the guitar, Perkins
    - Glyde Waltz
    - German Hymn
    - Saratoga Lake Waltz
    - Spanish Dance guitar music
    - Catabuna Quick Step
    - Ana's Waltz
    - Mary's Waltz
    - Harmonic Waltz
    - Good Hope Waltz
    - Elina Waltz for the guitar
    - Rail Road Waltz
    - Spanish Fandango
    - The Bunch of Flowers
    - The Melancholy
    - Dance
    - Star Waltz
    - Spanish Quick Step
    - O' Where and O Where is my Highland Laddie Gon with guitar accompaniment
    - Windham for the guitar
    - The American Flag words and music by W.D. Franklin
    - When Ye Going Ana Jamie poetry, arranged by John Demar
    - Farewell Glee by the Continentals
    - Charlotte Fitzpatrick
    - Untitled (possibly Sleep Well)
    - Dancing O'er the Waves
    - Let's Dance & Sing
    - Melody by Prof. Franklin, Harmonized by G.T.D.
    - Our Heroes
    - The Old Mountain Tree
  - Music, (hardbound book) (Folder 3)
    - A Song for the Union, poetry and music original
    - The Brave Volunteer, poetry and music by W.D. Franklin
    - The Brave Volunteer, poetry and music by W.D. Franklin
    - Aim Brothers Aim, poetry by Wm. Bourne
    - Rifle Regiment Set
    - Polka Set
    - Medley Set
    - Christy's Set
    - Glastenbury Franklin
    - Water Street, W.D. Franklin, July 27, 1862
    - Jones 7, (?) W.D. Franklin, July 31, 1862
    - Mary O'Conner
    - Farewell Song
    - A Very Funny Man
    - O Beautiful Spring
    - Mountain Bugle Song, music and poetry by W.D. Franklin
    - The Flag's Come Back to Tennepee, music by W.D. Franklin
    - O Care for them Tenderly, poetry by Bayard Taylor, music by W.D. Franklin
    - Yes, I Love Thee, poetry by W.J. Black, music by W.D. Franklin, Sandusky City, April 7 1855
    - Late One Lovely Summer Evening
    - Mus-i-cal Dialogue. Tenor and bass, poetry by Karamsin, music by W.D.F
    - Silver Wedding Song to Mr. and Mrs. Samuel Dimock of Rocky Hill
    - When the Joys of Youth Are O'er
    - Echo Song, poetry by Saxe
    - Spirit At Rest, written at Chicago, Illinois, April 14, 1864
    - Recollection of Home, composed by Chas. W. Huntington
    - The Magnolia of Old Tennessee
    - Lament for a Lost Canary Bird, dedicated to Mrs. J.H. Moore, poetry by Mrs. Perry
    - O Care for them Tenderly, poetry by Rev. G.D. Brewerton
    - Mountain Bugle Song, written at Harpers Ferry, Virginia, 1861
    - General Scott and Corporal Johnson, W.D. Franklin, So. Glastenbury, Ct.
    - Hark the Curfew, as sung by the Continentals of 1776 with revised edition as sung by The Franklin Quartette of 1875
    - Robin Ruff and Gaffer Green, by Henry Russell
  - Bound volume of published works (Box 5)
    Jennie A. Franklin on cover.
    - The National Union words and music by Charles Collins Jr.
    - Jeannie with the Light Brown Hair Fosters Melodies No. 26 written and composed by Stephen C. Foster
    - As I View These Scenes so Charming, Vi Raviso O Luoghi Ameni, Air, in the Celebrated Opera La Sonnambula composed by Bellini
    - The New Grand Opera 'Matilda' or the 'Maid of Hungary' written by Alfred Bunn, Esq.
    - The Morn Unbars the Gates of Light composed by E.A. Hosmer
    - The Danish Sea-King or Our Bark is on the Water's Deep sung bythe Pierian vocalists by Joseph W. Turner
    - Hark! Apollo Strikes the Lyre by H.R. Bishop
    - Schubert's La Serenade by Leopold Hoffman
    - Where Shall the Beautiful Rest by J.O. Starkweather
    - Wind of the Winter Night, Whence Comest Thou? by Henry Russell
    - Our Good Old Friends by Alice Hawthorne
    - A Cot Beside a Hill music of the Continental Vocalists, composed by J.A. Sterry
    - Echoing Horn by T. Wood
    - Our Home is on the Mountain's Brow by the Alleghanians
    - The Snow by James G. Maeder
    - Dermot Astore by F.N. Crouch
    - If Thoult Be Mine by Franz Petersilea
    - The Bridal Song by Franz Petersilea
    - My Home by Franz Petersilea
    - Home Sweet Home
    - My Eyes Are Dim With Tears J. Edgar Gould
    - The Skylark by J.L. Hatton
    - Say Will Summer Roses Bloom? by M.S.
    - Our Native Song by Henry Russell
    - The Freed Bird or Speed Away! Speed Away! On Thine Errand of Love by Joseph W. Turner
    - The Bloom is on the Rye by Henry R. Bishop
    - The Groves of Blarney Irish Ballad, piano accompanied by Beethoven
    - Shepard's Lay H. Heine
    - Thou Lovely Maid by F. Kucken
    - Serenade by Aug. Kreissmann
    - Years Ago by Charles E. Horn
    - The Wolf
    - Dumbartons Bonnie Dell by John Sinclair
    - Adieu Dear Native Land by Wm. Vincent Wallace
    - The Grave of Uncas by George H. Martin
    - Oh Native Scenes by Bellini
    - Hark I Hear an Angel Sing by J. Farrenburg
    - Soon My Harp Shall Silent Be by Pietro Centemeri
    - Oh As Fair as Poets Dreaming (Come E Bello) by Donizetti
    - I am the Only Thine
    - Oh! What Hopes at Their Height Balfe and Bunn
    - There's Sunlight in Heaven by M.W. Balfe
    - When All Around Our Path is Dreary Balfe and Bunn
    - Now Time Has Proved Thee False Balfe
    - Be This Moment the Brightest Balfe and Bunn
    - Yankee Quilting Party by John A. Sterry of the Alpine Warblers
    - Blue Beard
    - My Boyhood's Home by W.M. Rooke
    - How beautiful Is the Sea by J.W. Cherry
    - Depths of the Ocean by Carpenter and Glover
    - The Parting Requiem by Lewis Lavake
    - Those Evening Bells by Sir John Stevenson
    - The Three Calls or The Eleventh Hour by I.B. Woodbury
    - Good Night by Alfred Squire
    - Fond Hearts at Home by John R. Thomas
    - I'll Whisper to Thee by Carpenter and Hobbs
    - Oh! Whisper What Thou Feelest by W. Harrison
    - Birds of Spring by Mrs. L.B. Adams and Chas. Stein
    - Our Wildwood Home by Mrs. L.B. Adams and Chas. Stein
    - When the Night Grew Dark and Stormy by Jeffrey's and Bellini
    - Winnie Waters by J.H. Jones sung by Continental Vocalists
    - I'm Never Alone by W.D. Franklin
    - Wind and Sea by W.D. Franklin
    - My School Boy Days by W.D. Franklin
    - Sweet Dreams by Mrs. A.L.R. Defour and W.D. Franklin
    - A Hundred Years to Come by W.D. Franklin
    - The Cottage by the Glen by W.D. Franklin
    - Old Man's Soliloquy by W.D. Franklin
  - Large Bound Volume of Published Music (Box 6)
    - My Faith Looks Uo to thee thou Lamb of Calvary by Oliver J. Shaw
    - Jesus! Lover of My Soul by Oliver J. Shaw
    - There is Something Yet That Loves Me by W.D. Franklin
    - Song Should Breath of Fruits and Flowers by S. Laurence
    - Onward by J.P. Webster
    - Hurry Up the Good Time Coming J.P. Webster
    - Cora Bell by Bishop
    - Come Brothers, Come by Gates and Baker
    - I've Lost my Little May by Bishop
    - Come Let Us Gather 'Round the Hearth by L.D. Meignen
    - Spirit Voice of Bell Brandon by John B. Beardslee
    - Rest, Spirit, Rest by Haines and Rooke
    - Sweet and Low by H.S. Perkins
    - The Mariner Loves O'er the Waters to Roam by J. Gibson
    - Answer to Gentle Annie by J.P. Webster
    - Carry Me Home to Die by Leonard Grover
    - Come Lovely Spring by S. Wesley Martin
    - Those Village Chimes by A.F. Rockwell
    - Sweet Rivulet, Farewell by H.D.L. Webster
    - Fioravantes Singing Lesson by Charles E. Horn
    - Oh That I Were a Man of Wealth by J.P. Webster
    - The Joys of Harvest Home by Everett L. Baker
    - Where is the Sunny Land by J.R. Thomas
    - Let Us Try to be Happy by E.A. Perkins
    - The Sunbeams are Playing by Everett L. Baker
    - Shells of Ocean or I Wandered on the Sea Beat Shore by J.W. Cherry
    - Innocent Lena Romaine by Ossian E. Dodge
    - Dear Land of my Birth by George W. Griswold
    - Oh! Come to the Farmer's Cottage With Me by K.E. Ducat
    - Bella Lee by J.B. Beardslee
    - Our Father and Mother by J.C. Baker
    - The Moon's Pale Light is Beaming by J.B. Beardslee
    - Mary Aileen by J.H. McNaughton
    - In a Lone and Dreary Chamber by L.O. Emerson
    - Rejoice Greatly composed by Handel
    - Oh! Watch You Well by Daylight by Samuel Lover
    - Mother, I am Weary by J.P. Webster
    - Grandma's Advice by Kate E. Ducat
    - Birds of Spring by Chas. Stein
    - Thinks I to Myself by John C. Baker
    - Mother Do Not Weep or The Dying Boy by Frederick Buckley
    - The Battle Prayer by Himmel
    - Oh! Think of the Days That Are Past Stephen Glover
    - Ever of Thee by Foley Hall
    - Hard Times medley by T.M. Higgins
    - Cruel Love Dost Wring With Pleasure compsed by Mozart
    - Let me Go! My Feet Are Weary by E.A. Perkins
    - Going Up and Coming Down by Jos. P. Webster
    - Lorena by J.P. Webster
    - Maid of the Mill by Grace Richards
    - Ben Franklin's Grave by Stayman and Weiland
    - Burning Ship or Lost at Sea by L.W. Wheeler
    - Il Travatore G. Verdi
    - Alice Fling T.M. Higgins
    - Old Mill Wheel W. Milton Clark
    - The Valentine of The Spirit of Song by Libbie Higgins
    - The Manola by Paul Henrion
    - Fair Enchantress by J.G. Maeder
    - Dearest Spot by W.T. Wrighton
    - Loving Hearts at Home by J.R. Thomas
    - The Wanderer by F. Schubert
    - O Thou Queen of Love and Beauty by William J. Lemon
    - Slowly and Softly Music Should Flow by Stephen Glover
    - Old Man and the Child by F.G. Farrar
    - Oh Call Me Not Unkind Robin by Maria B. Hawes
    - Jennie Wright or Oh Say Wilt Thou be Mine by Mrs. A. Annie Wade
    - Out John and the Reply by Bayley and Dodge
    - Bright Days are Coming Love by J.R. Thomas
    - The Heart Bow'd Down by M.L. Balfe
    - Dew Drops of Morning Fall Cold on her Grave by J.P. Webster
    - Simon the Cellarer by J.L. Hatton
    - Youth and Age by C.F. Stein
    - There is Something Yet that Loves Me by W.D. Franklin